Ladies and gentlemen, so it's been
another week in AI and I think the lead
story of this week's episode of News You
Can Use is actually something that is
useful to almost anybody watching this
video. I mean, if you've ever worked
with Excel sheet or created a
PowerPoint, you will want to hear about
the new clot updates, but there's also
notebook element updates and nanobanana
use cases and a bunch of quick stories
that are super out there. We'll explore
all that and more in this week's episode
of AI News You can use the show that
rounds up all of this week's AI
releases, filters for the ones that
matter. and I have the pleasure of
presenting them back to you. So, with
that being said, let's dive into the
very first story of this week's show.
Okay, so for the main story this week,
we have something really exciting
because as you know, large language
models are extremely good at
transforming one type of thing into
another type of thing. But the one thing
it hasn't been able to consistently
produce is some of the files that are
most common in a professional work
environment. Excel sheets, PowerPoint
presentations, or word documents. Now
claude with this new update that is live
for everybody now went after this output
specifically. So when I log into my
claude account, you will see that it
introduced these new file types. Before
we use this, just go into your settings
and then under features, make sure you
have upgraded file creation and analysis
enabled for this to work. Let's see what
we can do here. So now in theory, I
should be able to create Excel sheets or
PowerPoint presentations that go beyond
anything that has been possible up until
now with these tools. And let me tell
you from everything that I've heard from
both my team and the internet, the
execution on this stands head and
shoulders above everything that we have
seen. But this show wouldn't be what it
is if we wouldn't actually put the
claims of the internet to the test. So
what I'm going to do in this case is I'm
going to open up a chat window and
compare it with a cloud generation. And
I'm just going to grab some data from
the past 28 days of the AI advantage
YouTube channel here and upload the CSV
both into claude and chat GPT. And I'm
going to take a prompt that is very
similar to what Enthropic did with their
launch video here. So I just tell it
that I attached YouTube analytics. Give
it a little bit of context on my
channel. And then I ask for the top
three to four opportunities with clear
visuals presented in Excel file.
Amazing. Just going to run this same
thing in GPT with the auto model router.
A few moments later.
>> Whoa, whoa, whoa. Okay, so first
impression is that I've seen many of
these files, but nothing comes even
close to what I'm seeing right here in
front of me. Okay, but like let's give
this a comprehensive view. So there's
five tabs within this Excel file. And
you know what? I'll actually download
this to compare it as our Lord intended
within Excel itself. Let's have a look
inside Excel. So look at that. One, two,
three, four, five. Damn. So this is the
raw data that we gave it, right? Then it
has a recommended content calendar for
the next 30 days. How to use cloth for
beginners ch. Oh my god, it wants me to
make all of these short tutorials. Okay,
interesting. Free eye tools every This
is actually really good. And like I want
to highlight the formatting here. Look
at how beautiful these are. I can tell
you if I were creating a sheet, it
wouldn't look this good. Not saying it's
perfect. Yeah, just saying this looks
really good. Okay, so it analyzed the
different components. Honestly, this is
just a fantastic way of looking at all
the data. Way better than this right
here. Wouldn't you agree? And then
here's the executive summary. Wow. I
guess I'm gonna be asking for all of my
results as a Excel file now. Okay. Not
bad. Not bad. But now let's make the
comparison, right? Because if we do the
same thing within chat GPT, it gave us
Excel file. And when we open that, we
get this right here. Okay. So this is
just the raw data right here. Top of
videos. Okay. It kind of just sorts it.
Opportunities. Oh, there's one. Okay.
So, as you can empty chart. So, as you
can see, this is not even close. I
figured it wouldn't be, but I didn't
think the gap would be this large. Now,
I'm sure OpenAI is going to catch up,
but as of now, claude. Wow, not bad.
Okay, I want to try one more thing
because this is supposed to be really
good with PowerPoints, too. So, I'm just
going to say turn it into a PowerPoint
presentation. Enter. Wait, hold up. This
even had a chart. I didn't see that.
Yeah, right here. Not bad. This is
impressive.
Okay, so this took about what? Five
minutes. Whoa, hold up. This is actually
good.
Okay, so YouTube channel analysis. My
god, it's like a consulting pitch deck.
And it's really clean. Are you serious?
>> And it's a completely different design
than the other one. So
>> yeah. Yeah. Yeah. With emojis, without
emojis, strategic emoji usage. This is
crazy good. I guess this is the only
obvious mistake here, this placement.
But come on, man. What can I say? Really
impressive. And as you know, you could
direct this, give it your brand's
colors. This is serious competition for
some of the specialized apps who do
presentations like Gamma, etc. Anyway,
my conclusion here is that this is
incredibly good. And if you ever tried
to make a sheet or a presentation or a
word document before, and you concluded
that LLMs are just not good at that,
well, it's time to reconsider and just
go ahead and try this for yourself, cuz
this was my very first attempt, and the
results that you get in a few minutes
are very, very clean. Wow. If you watch
the show, you know I don't say this very
often, but I'll be using this feature
all the time. Okay, let's move on. Okay,
so for the next story, we're going to be
looking at an upgrade that when I saw
it, I just figured this has been long
overdue in all VIP coding applications.
It's a update to Gemini Canvas where you
can create an application and then edit
it through visually clicking into it
instead of doing the whole screenshot
and describing stuff. Let's just give it
a shot. Okay, I'll just prompt it to
create a simple Pomodoro timer app and
then I can show you how this works.
Okay, so there it is as you would
expect. And now the innovation here is
that they added this visual editing. So
all you need to do is go down here and
use this new feature called select and
ask. So if I click this, I can just
select this button, make this bold, and
use a Japanese style gradient. I don't
know. It's just what came to mind. Okay,
so you know how we do it here. No
editing. So it didn't do this button. It
did the title. Let's give it one more
try. A similar prompt. I'll just say
that it should complement the color
scheme. Let's see if it gets it right
this time. Maybe it was because I just
selected the middle and not the whole
element. That's really giving it a lot
of credit though. I hope it gets it
right on this second try. Okay, so that
actually worked perfectly. This is sort
of what I had in mind. Although some of
the other functionality doesn't work
yet. We could fix that though. I just
wanted to show you this feature because
I think this is the direction that these
things are heading in. I mean, let's be
real. Vibe coding and taking screenshots
and then describing which part of the
screenshot you mean and how you want it
edited is not optimal. And tools like
this just make it simpler. If this
worked flawlessly, it would make me
question why not all VIP coding apps
actually have this already. And I'm sure
over time we'll get this across the
other applications too. Nice update to
the editing canvas. And as you saw, it
might not always work flawlessly. Next
up, we have notebook LM shipping even
more updates. If you follow the show,
then you might have seen that across the
past few weeks, we got updates and we
also posted a great tutorial on the
channel introducing you to Notebook LM
and now they have a new reports feature
with flashcards and quizzes rolling out
slowly. So, let's just give this a brief
look as we usually do on this channel.
I'll just open up this cloth code
workbook with a bunch of YouTube videos.
And as you can see, if I go to reports,
you'll get a bunch of new options here.
You can do a custom report or one of
these presets here. And what I really
like is they added a AI suggestions
feature. So down here it suggests what
type of report would make sense here. So
in the case of this clot code workbook,
maybe a onboarding guide or a process
explainer. That actually makes a lot of
sense. I'm just going to generate one of
those and see what we get there.
Okay, so it took about 2 minutes and now
we have our report right here. So this
was the process explainer, right? And
essentially what it did here is a
beginner guide, a step-by-step guide. So
it starts with step one. You need
NodeJS, install CL code, etc. Okay, that
looks really solid. Then crafting the
prompt. Yeah, I mean this looks really
solid and includes some of the tips.
We're sell hosting Firebase for the back
end here. So, this is fantastic. It
basically produces a guide from all of
these sources and give some advanced
techniques in the end. Great stuff. I
really like these reports, especially
these suggested formats that it comes up
with on the fly. One of the most
powerful apps in the space becoming even
more capable. So for the next story,
we're going to be looking at some
various use cases as recommended by
Google by one of the most popular apps
across the entire AI space recently, the
image editing model, NanoBanana, also
known as Google 2.5 flash editing. I
don't even know. It's Nano Banana. Okay.
>> Okay.
>> And let's be real, for long-term
followers of this channel, you might
notice that the main example they did
here, this cat with a hat, is something
that yours truly right here uses every
single time. Okay, I didn't come up with
it, right? Like originally I think this
is a Borat joke.
>> Is this a cat in a hat?
>> But Google is doing cats with hats too
at this point in time. This is an
industry standard way to show off image
editing capabilities. Point here is they
show a few use cases and one of them is
adding and removing elements with this
cat with a hat example. Here's the
specific prompt for that. The link to
this thread will be in the description.
You can just get it from there. Next up,
they show one that we featured in this
week's newsletter, which is in painting,
aka making selective edits to only a
part of the image. And how to do that
with this specific prompt right here.
And then a few more. You can mix
multiple images like a dress and a
picture of a woman to get the woman in
the dress. And then lastly, adding this
logo to her t-shirt. So, if you're
looking for inspiration or prompts for
Nana Banana, there you go. There's four
really powerful ones that you can take,
customize, and use for yourself. And if
you haven't given this a shot yet or you
were living in a cave over the past few
weeks, then this is your reminder to go
and play with Nano Banana because it's
unbelievable.
It really raised the bar on what is
expected from AI image generation
models, especially when it comes to
editing existing images. Like as you can
see, it maintains the actual face of the
person instead of morphing it just like
chat would before. Okay, let's see
what's next. In other news, OpenAI is
trying to depreciate the standard voice
mode in chatbt and they're trying to
replace him with the advanced voice mode
that you might know. That's kind of the
interactive voice and the blob that
moves around. And even people within our
community are pushing back on this and
saying they like the standard voice
mode. I wasn't even aware that this is a
thing. And so many people share this
opinion that OpenAI implemented a new
feature that if you go to customize chat
GPT and you go to advanced down here,
you can disable advanced voice mode for
yourself. So, if I do that and then use
voice mode, you will see that this is
not advanced mode. This one is just the
old voice mode. There's no color.
>> Got it. Sounds like you're pointing out
that the current voice mode experience.
Probably in the chat GPT mobile app or
similar isn't using the new advanced
voice mode.
>> And then apparently people prefer this
to this experience. Hey, so how's this
different?
>> You got it. I'll keep it nice and
straightforward. Basically, I'm just
going to focus on giving you the kind of
clear, nononsense advice.
>> Okay. Can I interrupt you?
>> Absolutely. To me, it feels like that
the old voice mode is more static and
the new one is a bit more flowy, but
then to me, the quality of the old one
seems a bit higher because it's not
trying to have a fluid conversation. It
kind of just talks and then you can
pause it and let it talk if you prefer
that. Now, there's an option to switch
around. Okay, let's see what's next. So,
now we get into the quick hit segment
where we talk about various stories that
are worth your attention, but maybe we
don't need to speak about them for
multiple minutes. Starting with a brand
new paper on why language models
hallucinate. You can certainly get into
it. What I did is I just ran it through
this summarizer prompt and I like the
second summary the most. And it
essentially explains how all language
models are trained to sound very
confident because they're training and
most exams reward guessing over
admitting certainty. And then the author
of the paper also suggests that you
could change how you score the exams so
that in the training the model also gets
credit for saying I don't know
sometimes. As of now, just be aware of
this and know that the models will
confirm a lot of information just
because that's the way they're trained.
Next up, we have something that you
can't use immediately, but very soon the
new AirPods Pro Free are available. And
they announced a AI feature, live
translation, which I'm extremely
interested in. I'll be getting these.
I'll be testing that out, reporting back
to you on this channel, maybe even in
this show. But essentially, they're
going to be using the active noise
cancellation to suppress what you hear
and playing a live translation that is
processed on your iPhone. All of the
current AI translation apps are kind of
bad. So, I can't wait to see what Apple
does here. Also, in other news, Claude
rolled out this feature that allows you
to connect to various service called
permissions and you can give it access
to your location, your calendar or
reminders. This is something we find in
chat GPT already in other ways. So, for
example, in chat GPT by connecting to
map provider, it seems to get your
location. That's my understanding at
least. Whereas here, you can set it up
like so and ask for local restaurant
recommendations. And then it has your
location because you gave it that
permission. The next story is a very
interesting product category. If you
haven't seen this, this is called alter
ego. And from the launch video, it looks
like a device that reads your mind, but
really when you look beyond the surface,
you realize that you actually have to
vocalize the things that it reads out
loud. So you're making noises and moving
your tongue. It's just so silent that
it's not audible to the outside world
and then the device picks it up. But
still, this could be an interesting AI
interface in certain situations where
you're not allowed to speak. You could
kind of just
>> Sorry, I can't hear you.
>> I don't know. Is that even audible?
>> No, I literally can't hear you.
>> Apparently, this device picks it up.
>> Oh, I can hear you now.
>> And should be coming soon. Interesting.
For the next story, it's just a
follow-up to a model that we've seen
before. It's called Tripo, and now they
released 3.0. It's from the folks over
at Stable Diffusion. It's a text or
image to 3D model. So, if you work in
that space or play around with Blender,
make sure to check it out. It looks
really good. That's it. Then we also
have some updates in the image
generation arena. So Midjourney
introduced this new feature that they
call style explorer where you can
explore various styles on this page and
then if you like one of them there's a
button that says try styles and then you
can reapply to your own images.
Similarly but different ideoggram now
also introduced styles. This app is very
popular with graphic design related
tasks. So if you work in that space and
you want to maintain consistent styles
or you have a few styles that you manage
for a brand, you can now do that really
easily. And then the last quick hit for
this week is actually a use case that I
really enjoyed. It's this video from
Runway where they're showing how to use
a feature that we introduced on the show
a few weeks ago where you can edit
videos to create these so-called warers
where it's just one shot with a bunch of
visual effects in the middle. And then
here's a tutorial. Just shoot your scene
and chop it up into 5-second exports.
And then for each clip, you can apply
new effects. So, for example, now that
we're done with the content of this
video, we could just splice this up and
have this happen. I mean, editing team,
I hope you came up with something fun
for that. But other than that, I hope
you found something that's useful or at
the very least inspirative to you. And
with that being said, my name is Igor
and I hope you have a wonderful